{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The r in 'red'","incorrectAnswers":["The ch in 'cheese'","The t in 'train'","The sh in 'shop'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of an approximant sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist, singer, songwriter, musician and record producer released the studio album 'The Sensual World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Donkey Engine","incorrectAnswers":["Gabelle","Grommet","Yarborough"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a small auxiliary engine on a ship'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Too Much Happiness'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lactic acid","incorrectAnswers":["Amenic Acid","Stomach Acid","Pectic Acid"],"question":"What chemical compound causes pain in muscles after exercise?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Janissaries","incorrectAnswers":["Samurai","Ghazis","Sipahis"],"question":"What were the Ottoman Empire’s elite slave infantrymen called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Carrie","incorrectAnswers":["Star Wars","The Godfather","Jaws"],"question":"The line \"There're all gonna laugh at you\" is from which 70's film?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"General Electric","incorrectAnswers":["IBM","Apple","Tesla"],"question":"What company uses the slogan \"Imagination at Work\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cake","incorrectAnswers":["Cured Meat","Cheese","Pickled Vegetables"],"question":"Traditional in Germany at Christmas, what sort of food is stollen?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Javelin throw","Archery","Karate"],"question":"Which of these sports uses a ball?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Dead Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Red Sea","Death Valley","The Grand Canyon"],"question":"Which body of water is the Earth's lowest point on land, reaching more than 1,300 feet below sea level?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Ummagumma'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Thousand","incorrectAnswers":["Hundred","Million","Few"],"question":"What is the number missing from the Khaled Hosseini book title: 'A ___ Splendid Suns'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Simon Bolivar","incorrectAnswers":["Hugo Chavez","Fidel Castro","Che Guevara"],"question":"Which Venezuelan wrote the \"Cartagena Manifesto\", a famous essay on independence, in December 1812?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer released the studio album 'I Am… Sasha Fierce'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Uralic","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Koreanic","Indo-European"],"question":"The language 'Hungarian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Art Nouveau","incorrectAnswers":["Pop Art","Fauvism","Impressionism"],"question":"Which decorative art movement emerged in the late nineteenth century and was characterized by dense assymmetrical ornamentation in sinuous forms?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Severance","incorrectAnswers":["Squid Game","Split","Mr Robot"],"question":"Released in 2022, which TV show depicts a world where people undergo a procedure to split their mind into two so that they can enjoy life without work?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Phillipines","incorrectAnswers":["Romania","Turkey","Estonia"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink tuba?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Talus","incorrectAnswers":["Tibia","Fibia","Metatarsal"],"question":"What is the second largest bone in the foot?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mama Juana","incorrectAnswers":["Gin","Maotai","Chibuku"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in The Dominican Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Hippocratic Oath","incorrectAnswers":["The Nightingale's Pledge","The Socratic Oath","The Ecclesiast Pledge"],"question":"What is the name of the oath traditionally taken by doctors, which originated in ancient Greece and is still associated with the medical profession today?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1993","incorrectAnswers":["1989","1997","2001"],"question":"In which year was Schindler's List first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":" Central Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Eastern Europe","Western Australia"],"question":"Where are the Altai mountains located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Horse","incorrectAnswers":["Lion","Moose","Swan"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Ferrari logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Parmesan","incorrectAnswers":["Cheddar","Gouda","Feta"],"question":"What type of cheese is Parmigiano Reggiano?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Port Louis","incorrectAnswers":["Luanda","Johannesburg","Rabat"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Mauritius?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Atlanta United","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta Impact","Atlanta Bulls","Atlanta Stars"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Atlanta?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Flies","incorrectAnswers":["Schematics","The interpretation of symbols","Ligaments"],"question":"What is Dipterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Burundi","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Slovenia","Turkmenistan"],"question":"Gitega is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Two vertical bands of red with white square between them containing a red leaf.","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon with a broad white serrated band on the left side.","Green, with large white script and a sword.","Red with a white cross that extends to the edges."],"question":"What does the flag of Canada look like?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hawaii","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Alaska","Maine"],"question":"Which US state gets the most rainfall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cairo","incorrectAnswers":["Conakry","Nairobi","Alexandria"],"question":"What is the capital city of Egypt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Midnight Cowboy","incorrectAnswers":["The Graduate","A Clockwork Orange","Last Tango in Paris"],"question":"What was the first X-rated film to win Best Picture at the Academy Awards?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henri Rousseau","incorrectAnswers":["Raphael","‎Pablo Picasso","Vasily Kandinsky"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Sleeping Gypsy\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cranberries","incorrectAnswers":["The Corrs","Boyzone","Thin Lizzy"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the single 'Zombie'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Snorri Sturluson","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Prose Edda'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Emerson, Lake & Palmer","incorrectAnswers":["Supertramp","UB40","Editors"],"question":"Which English progressive rock band released the song 'Lucky Man'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Connect Four","incorrectAnswers":["Chess","Clue","Monopoly"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must create a path of dots from one side of the board to the other?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gin ","incorrectAnswers":["Rum","Vodka","Whiskey"],"question":"Which Spirit Is Pimm's No 1 Based On?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Die Hard","incorrectAnswers":["The Big Lebowski","Citizen Kane","Raiders of the Lost Ark"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'John McClane'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jack Swigert","incorrectAnswers":["Buzz Aldrin","Sally Ride","John Glen"],"question":"What Apollo 13 astronaut contacted Mission Control with the words, \"Houston, we've had a problem\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Leek ","incorrectAnswers":["Carrot","Potato","Onion"],"question":"Which vegetable is also a Welsh emblem?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Common People","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Suede Shoes","Because the Night","Red Red Wine"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by Pulp, was later covered by William Shatner?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Columbus Crew","incorrectAnswers":["Columbus Kings","Columbus Bruins","Columbus Dolphins"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Columbus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Buck","A Dog","A Drone"],"question":"What is the word for a male bear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Opel","incorrectAnswers":["Honda","Ferrari","Rolls-Royce"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Astra?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"King's Cross","incorrectAnswers":["Waterloo","Charing Cross","Paddington"],"question":"From which London railway station does Harry Potter catch the Hogwart's Express?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Chicken Marengo ","incorrectAnswers":["Chicken Kiev","Hunter's Chicken","Chicken Supreme"],"question":"Which chicken dish is named after a battle in the Napoleonic wars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"National Aeronautics and Space Administration","incorrectAnswers":["National Astronaut and Shuttle Association","National Aerospace and Shuttle Administration","National Aerospace and Space Association"],"question":"What does the acronym NASA stand for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1979","incorrectAnswers":["1974","1984","1989"],"question":"In which year was Alien first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Soccer","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Horse Racing","Basketball"],"question":"In what sport would you use the terms 'Corner', 'Header' and 'Bicycle'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Washington Color School","incorrectAnswers":["Crystal Cubism","Primitivism","Ukiyo-e"],"question":"The painting \"Royal Red and Blue\" by Mark Rothko is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Which would be worse, to live a monster or die as a good man?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Release the Kraken!\"","\"A martini. Shaken, not stirred.\"","\"I want to be alone.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Shutter Island'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Laos","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Singapore","Ivory Coast"],"question":"Larb is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Marvin Gaye","incorrectAnswers":["Otis Redding","James Brown","Wilson Pickett"],"question":"Which Motown singer did an album called \"Here, My Dear\" to pay for his divorce?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kim Basinger","incorrectAnswers":["Sally Hawkins","Lucy Lawless","Jacqueline Bisset"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Batman and Never Say Never Again?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the song 'Bridge over Troubled Water'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Japonic","Austronesian","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Yue Chinese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Samoa","incorrectAnswers":["Mauritius","Croatia","Djibouti"],"question":"Apia is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Queen Mary","incorrectAnswers":["The Titanic","The Queen Victoria","The Olympic"],"question":"Which great ocean liner sailed its maiden voyage in 1934?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The liver","incorrectAnswers":["Religion","The moon","The number 7"],"question":"What is Hepatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Slovakia","incorrectAnswers":["Hungary","Germany","Portugal"],"question":"Bratislava is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Johannes Kepler","incorrectAnswers":["Galileo Galilei","Isaac Newton","René Descartes"],"question":"Who became imperial mathematician to the Holy Roman Emperor in 1601 after the death of Tycho Brahe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which musician released the album 'Off the Wall'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sierra Leone","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Slovakia","Sri Lanka"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sl' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain & Portugal ","incorrectAnswers":["North Korea & South Korea","Italy & Albania","Greece & North Macedonia"],"question":"Which 2 Countries Occupy The Iberian Peninsula? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Aquinas","Diogenes","Friedrich Nietzsche"],"question":"Who said all things were made up of air, earth, fire, and water?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cambodia","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Mongolia","Singapore"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Phnom Penh?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bambi","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Pan","Dumbo","Pinocchio"],"question":"From which 1942 animated film is a skunk named Flower?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which musician wrote the song 'Blowin' in the Wind'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Costa Rica","France","Singapore"],"question":"Ceviche is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tirana","incorrectAnswers":["Ankara","Addis Ababa","Tallinn"],"question":"What is the capital city of Albania?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Rosetta Stone","incorrectAnswers":["The Philosopher's Stone","The Stone of Destiny","The Cornerstone"],"question":"What is the name of the ancient stone tablet that was carved in 196 B.C., and helped scholars decipher Egyptian hieroglyphs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Bahamas","Trinidad and Tobago","Argentina"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Belo Horizonte?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["CR-V","Model T","3-Series"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Volkswagen?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Cedric Diggory' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Drone","incorrectAnswers":["A Buck","A Jack","A Boar"],"question":"What would you call a male bee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gandalf","incorrectAnswers":["Saruman","Radagast","Merlin"],"question":"In J.R.R. Tolkien's Middle-earth stories, which wizard gets promoted from \"the Grey\" to \"the White\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Charlize Theron","incorrectAnswers":["Keisha Castle-Hughes","Diane Keaton","Samantha Morton"],"question":"Who won the 2003 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Aileen Wuornos in Monster?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Elliot Ness","incorrectAnswers":["Chris Robson","Dave Bradzinski","Arthur Montgomery"],"question":"Which F.B.I agent headed the investigation of Al Capone? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"animals","incorrectAnswers":["the lymph system and glands","the nature of values and value judgements","the mnemonic practice of writing sentences such that the numbers of letters in the words correspond to the consecutive digits of pi"],"question":"What is Zoology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kesha","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Nicki Minaj","Aretha Franklin"],"question":"Which American singer released the studio album 'Animal'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎Pablo Picasso","incorrectAnswers":["Pieter Bruegel the Elder","Jackson Pollock","Jacques-Louis David"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Guernica\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Black Eyed Peas","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band includes 'will.i.am'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Greece ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Switzerland","Croatia"],"question":"Where Might You Drink The Wine Retsina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Spacey","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Jean-Claude Van Damme","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including House of Cards and Superman Returns?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Prague ","incorrectAnswers":["St Petersberg","Oxford","Vienna"],"question":"Which European city is nicknamed \"The city of a hundred spires\" and has tourist attractions including St Vitus Cathedral and Charles Bridge?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gruyère","incorrectAnswers":["Mozzarella","Feta","Gouda"],"question":"Which type of cheese is used to make fondue?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Children's behavior and development","incorrectAnswers":["Male health and disease","Religion","The anatomy of the cardiovascular system"],"question":"What is Paedology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Singapore","Uzbekistan","Russia"],"question":"Meat Pie is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antarctica","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Africa","North America"],"question":"______________ is the only continent without reptiles or snakes","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Bridge on the River Kwai","incorrectAnswers":["Goodfellas","The 400 Blows","Joker"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'POWs are forced to build a railway, not knowing that allies are planning to destroy it.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tripoli","incorrectAnswers":["Benghazi","Tunis","Alexandria"],"question":"What is the capital of Libya?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blur","incorrectAnswers":["Pulp","Oasis","Shed Seven"],"question":"Which British band did Damon Albarn lead?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Eel fishing","incorrectAnswers":["Bear hunting","Hawking","Crabbing"],"question":"What are you doing when you are sniggling?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The North Star","incorrectAnswers":["Orion's Belt","The Sun","Alpha Centauri"],"question":"As what is Polaris also known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Athletics","Rugby Union","Surfing"],"question":"With which sport is George Best associated?","difficulty":"hard"},